so we're on one we are on page 145 I
所以我们就在第145页上
believe a wife's roles in marriage there
相信妻子在那里结婚的角色
are more than one and that's why I have
不止一个，这就是我的原因
that word being plural here's my
这个词是复数这里是我的
introduction which matters more the
更重要的介绍
heart or the mind both are important to
心脏或心灵都很重要
be sure each can bring glory to God
要确保每一个人都能为上帝带来荣耀
and each can also oppose God in the
每个还可以在 反对神
context of today's topic a wife's roles
今天主题的背景是妻子的角色
in marriage I say the heart matters more
在婚姻中我说心更重要
consider these fats Romans 10:9 with the
考虑这些脂肪罗马书10：9与
heart one believes and is justified
心中有人相信并且是有道理的
faith in the gospel accompanied by the
对福音的信仰伴随着福音
decision of the will to repent turning
意志决定悔改转向
from the life of serving sin to the life
从服务罪的生活到生命
of serving God are both acts of the
侍奉上帝既是行为的
heart we only believe because God chose
我们只相信因为上帝的选择
us before the foundation of the world
我们在 世界建立之前
Ephesians 1 4 and 5 and the heart
以弗所书1 4和5以及心脏
believes and repents at the point of
相信在点忏悔
salvation the heart matters more point
救赎心更重要
number 2 this is all our introduction
2号，这是我们所有的介绍
God places a greater emphasis on the
神放置在更加强调
heart for the wife's roles than for the
为妻子的角色而不是为了
husbands the husband is to do actions
丈夫丈夫是做行动的
lay down his life work to provide for
放下他的生活工作来提供
the physical needs of the wife lead her
妻子的身体需要引导她
help her grow in sanctification serve
帮助她在成圣服务中成长
her in the intimate moments
她在亲密的时刻
certainly in each of those there are
当然在每一个都有
some heart or will components but most
一些心脏或组件，但大多数
of the man's role in the marriage is
该男子在婚姻中的角色是
action
行动
the wife's roles on the other hand
另一方面 ，妻子的角色
focused primarily on the heart the will
主要关注意志的核心
the desires God gives the wife these
上帝赐给妻子这些欲望
things to do as part of her role respect
作为她角色尊重的一部分，要做的事情
the husband submit to him love him do
丈夫顺服他爱他
him good and not harm fear nothing other
他善良而不伤害别人
than God for the five of those our heart
比神五个那些我们的心脏
matters we're going to talk about each
我们将讨论每个问题
of those in a minute but I'm still in
一分钟但我还在
the introduction although each of these
引入虽然每个这些
has that action component for the wife
有妻子的那个动作组件
the motive behind the action is the key
行动背后的动机是关键
to doing God's will it's the key for the
做上帝的旨意，这是关键
wife to obeying God in four of those
妻子在其中的四个中服从上帝
five things I think this shows the
我认为这显示了五件事
wisdom of women
女人的智慧
God gives us as men tasks to do but for
上帝赐给我们作为人类的任务，但是为了
the women less instruction on what to do
女性较少指导该做什么
is needed the women need to just get the
女人需要得到的
motive right that's the emphasis in
动机权利是强调的
these things the woman who fears God and
这些事谁敬畏神，女人
respects her husband doesn't require as
尊重她的丈夫不要求
many as instructions as guys do on the
很多像男人那样的指示
how-to of doing these things she can
如何做 她能做的 这些事情
figure it out for herself I think that's
为自己弄清楚我认为那是
the implication that's the wisdom of a
这是一个智慧的寓意
woman well the heart matters more point
女人心里更重要点
three think about this one
三个想到这个
after Adam's sin in the garden the curse
亚当在花园里犯罪后的诅咒
for the woman according to Genesis 3:16
根据创世纪3:16的女人
has two parts first the multiplied pain
有两个部分首先是倍增的痛苦
in childbirth and the second one is the
分娩时，第二个是分娩
desire against the husband the desire to
渴望对丈夫的渴望
rule over the husband this even though
尽管如此，对丈夫的统治
God gives the husband the place of
上帝赐予丈夫的地位
authority over the wife
对妻子的权威
is it not true that a frequent core
频繁的核心是不是真的
problem for women in marriage is that
婚姻中的女性问题是
they try to control their husbands women
他们试图控制自己的丈夫
have this tendency and have had this
有这种倾向，并有这个
inherent temptation since the fall so
自秋天以来固有的诱惑
for the wives the heart that is the will
对于妻子是 意志的心脏
the motive the desires the heart matters
心灵渴望的动机
most going on a little further with my
与上一点点最会进一步我
introduction still no notes in front of
介绍前面还没有任何笔记
you but here we go I wanted to talk
你但我们走了， 我想谈谈
about why the heart matters most for the
关于心脏最重要的原因
wife in regard to her roles God tests
妻子关于她的角色上帝测试
the hearts of men and women
男人和女人的心
proverbs 17 3 says then second
谚语17 3然后说第二
chronicles 16:9 says that God searches
编年史16：9说上帝搜查
the whole earth and he's looking for
整个地球，他在寻找
something what's he looking for
什么是他想要的东西
he's searching for the heart that is
他寻找那就是心脏
completely his so today God is testing
今天完全是他的上帝正在测试
the hearts of Christian wives and he's
基督徒妻子和他的心
searching for the hearts that are
寻找那些心灵
completely committed to obeying him what
完全致力于顺从他的是什么
does it look like when he finds such a
他发现这样的时候看起来像什么？
woman some scriptures answer that she
女人有些经文回答她
does what is right without being
做正确的事而不
frightened by any fear first Peter 3:6
彼得前书3：6被任何恐惧吓坏了
she's submissive to her husband first
她首先顺从她的丈夫
Peter 3 5 not because of anything that
彼得3 5不是因为任何
he is or anything that he isn't but
他是或者他不是的任何东西
because she hopes in God in the hidden
因为她希望隐藏在上帝里面
person of the heart that's first Peter 3
第一个彼得3的心脏的人
4 and 5 proverbs 31 29 and 30 say it
4 和5谚语31 29和30说出来
this way many daughters have done nobly
这样很多女儿都做得很高兴
but you excel them all the woman who
但你擅长所有那些女人
fears the Lord she shall be praised the
害怕主，她将受到称赞
heart does matter most and what matters
心最重要，重要的是什么
most in the heart the heart that honors
最内心的是荣耀的心
God as God in every part of life the key
上帝在生活的每一个方面都是上帝的关键
to wives living the roles found in God's
为妻子生活在上帝的角色中
Word is the heart the woman who fears
言语是担心的女人的心
God and not man including her husband
上帝而不是包括她丈夫在内的人
the woman who does not strive to rule
不努力统治的女人
her husband the woman who fears and
她的丈夫是害怕的女人
honors the Lord that woman is putting
尊重女人所赐的主
her trust in God I believe that for
她相信上帝我相信 ，
Christian women who are married the key
结婚的基督徒女性的关键
to living your biblical roles well is
很好地生活你的圣经角色
the heart if you are driven by the heart
如果你被心脏驱使的话
purpose of pleasing God you'll gladly
你很高兴地取悦上帝的目的
fulfill these roles that God lays out
履行上帝所规定的这些角色
for you and be able to figure out how to
为你而且能够弄清楚如何
do so whether you are married to a great
无论你是嫁给一个伟大的人，都要这样做
Christian man or a woeful sinner
基督徒或可怜的罪人
similarly the woman who gives in to that
同样的女人谁给到该
cursed desire to rule over the man
诅咒统治这个男人的欲望
will do so whether he is a godly man or
无论他是虔诚的人还是虔诚的人，他都会这样做
not even saved often the key in
甚至没有经常保存钥匙
counseling Christian wives is this one
咨询基督徒的妻子就是这个
thing her repentance from the purpose of
她悔改的目的
controlling her husband and then
控制她的丈夫然后
replacing that with the righteous desire
更换与正义的愿望
of honoring God my wife Julie and I have
尊重上帝我的妻子朱莉和我
seen this so many times when the harsh
当苛刻的时候见过这么多次
dissatisfied controlling bitter woman
控制苦涩的女人不满意
shifts from protecting herself due to
由于保护自己而改变
fears due to the desire of wanting to
由于渴望的欲望而产生的恐惧
make the final decisions due to the
由于这个原因做出最终决定
wanting to protect our kids from our
想要保护我们的孩子免受我们的伤害
husband's foolishness
丈夫的愚蠢
when that woman changes from that to
当那个女人从那个变为
honoring God as her purpose
尊重上帝是她的目的
the wife's roles become easy for her why
妻子的角色对她来说变得容易了
because she's no longer in measure she's
因为她不再适合她了
no longer measuring the day by control
不再通过控制来衡量一天
and has everything right she's measuring
并且她正在测量一切正确
it by how well did she trust God and how
它是如何信任上帝的，以及如何
well did she do the the good works that
她做了那些好作品
God sovereignly wove into those that
上帝主权地对那些那些人进行了修改
day's events why the heart matters most
一天的事件为什么心脏最重要
a final thought the heart matters even
最后的想法，心脏甚至是重要的
more in the next life I hope you're all
在接下来的生活中我希望你能成为更多
convinced by now that the there's a
现在确信那里有一个
great importance of the heart today but
今天心灵非常重要但是
first Corinthians 4:5 describes the Bema
哥林多前书4：5描述了Bema
seat judgment of believers at this point
在这一点上对信徒的判断
Christians people who are saved for
基督徒被拯救的人
eternity and are there with God will be
永恒，与上帝同在
judged not for the purpose of judgment
判断不是判断的目的
Jesus took the punishment upon us
耶稣接受了我们的惩罚
already in the price for our sin but
已经在为我们的罪而付出代价了
this judgment will be for the purpose of
这个判决将是为了
rewards what will happen God will give
奖励上帝会给予什么
each Christian woman who was married
每个结婚的基督徒女人
along with every other Christian a crown
与其他基督徒一起成为王冠
each crown will have a different amount
每个冠将有不同的数量
of jewels based on what we did here on
根据我们在这里所做的事情来看珠宝
earth ladies jewels
地球女士珠宝
it will be a great privilege for each of
对每个人来说都是一个很大的荣幸
us to lay that crown at the feet of
我们把那个王冠放在脚下
Jesus Christ because we'll all think the
耶稣基督，因为我们都会想到
same thing on that day Lord it all the
在那一天同样的事情主啊
glory belongs to you anything that was
光荣属于你的东西，这是
anything in my life is because you are
我生命中的任何事情都是因为你
my Lord and because of what you did on
我的主，因为你做了什么
the cross
十字
we'll all recognize on that day that it
我们都会在那一天认出它
was his credit not ours
他的功劳不是我们的
but thinking about this ladies if
但想想这位女士们
because of your love for Jesus Christ
因为你对耶稣基督的爱
because of how much you honored God
因为你多么尊敬上帝
above everything else and whatever the
高于一切，无论如何
circumstances of your marriage happened
你婚姻的情况发生了
to be during the years on earth there
在那里的那些年里
are more huge jewels in that crown that
是那个王冠中更大的珠宝
you'll be able to lay at the feet of
你将能够躺在脚下
Jesus Christ is that not worth it
耶稣基督是不值得的
doesn't that put it all into perspective
并没有把这一切都放在眼里
do you not want or that moment I do we
你不想要或那一刻我做我们
each desire that greatly because Jesus
因耶稣而极大的渴望
Christ is our Lord
基督是我们的主
so first Corinthians 4:5 explains this
所以哥林多前书4：5首先解释了这一点
judgment describing the Lord as the one
将主描述为一个人的判断
who think about this quote we'll bring
谁想到我们带来的这句话
to light the things now hidden in the
点亮现在藏在里面的东西
darkness and will disclose the purposes
黑暗并将披露目的
of the heart then each one will receive
然后每个人都会收到心脏
his condemnation or his thing sorry I
他的谴责或他的事对不起我
got to say this right then each one will
必须说出来，然后每个人都会
receive his commendation from God this
从上帝那里得到他的称赞
is the believers before God so today our
是上帝面前的信徒所以今天是我们的
purposes are hidden why does that
目的是隐藏的原因
Christian wife do that we don't really
基督徒的妻子这样做， 我们不是真的
know but God knows on that day everyone
知道，但天知道那天大家都知道
will know and the fact is God already
会知道，事实就是上帝
knows
知道
on that day you and I will stand before
那天你和我会站在那里
him and he will reveal what only he and
他， 他会揭示了什么只有他和
we know now why we do what we do the
我们现在知道为什么我们做什么我们做的
heart the heart matters most wives are
心脏的心脏最重要的是妻子
tempted by the desire to control their
受到控制他们的欲望的诱惑
husbands it's universal since the curse
丈夫自诅咒以来就是普遍的
yet the wife who chooses in her heart to
然而，在她心中选择的妻子
honor God as her ruling motive
尊重上帝作为她的统治动机
regardless of the circumstances she
不管她的情况如何
respects and submits and does good to
尊重和提交并做好事
her husband regardless of who he is and
不管他是谁，她的丈夫
that woman is bringing great glory and
那个女人带来了巨大的荣耀
honor to the Lord Jesus Christ and those
尊重主耶稣基督和那些人
motives will be revealed one day for
动机将被揭示一天的时间
God's glory and really to her blessing
上帝的荣耀，真的是她的祝福
in eternity so the heart matters most
在永恒中，心脏最重要
let's take a look at the wife's roles
让我们来看看妻子的角色
the wife's roles first a respect
妻子的角色首先是尊重
Ephesians 5:22 and 33 the respect for
以弗所书5:22 和33尊重
the husband has to do with your response
丈夫与你的回应有关
to God not your husband's worthiness a
上帝不是你丈夫的价值
significant part of the wife's respect
妻子尊重的重要部分
is the wife's response to the husband's
是妻子对丈夫的回应
effort to fulfill his roles so wives are
努力履行他的职责，所以妻子是
to respect their husbands because that
尊重他们的丈夫因为那样
is part of what God gives them to do be
是上帝赐给他们的一部分
the wife is to submit to her husband I'd
妻子要服从她的丈夫
like to offer here a biblical
喜欢在这里提供一个圣经
perspective on submission we as
关于提交我们的观点
Christians are all subject to God's
基督徒都受到上帝的
authority because above all else because
权威，因为最重要的是因为
he is the Lord
他是主
but God has also created other a Thor
但是上帝也创造了另一个雷神
to be responsible over us and to rule
对我们负责和统治
over us so the authorities that we have
在我们这样的机构，我们有
our first God over us Galatians 5:16 and
我们的第一个上帝对我们加拉太书5:16和
17 Jesus as an authority over us John
17耶稣作为对我们的权威约翰
3:36 church elders are an authority over
3:36教会长老是权威
us we are to submit to their leadership
我们要服从他们的领导
and to obey them it says in Hebrews
在希伯来书中说，要遵守它们
13:17 the government is an authority
13:17政府是权威
over us Romans 13:1 2:7 we all are to
罗马书13：1 2：7我们都要这样
submit to the authority of the
服从的权威
government and the Roman government was
政府和罗马政府是
less Christian friendly than the US
基督徒比美国更少友好
government today of course there's an
今天政府当然有一个
exception for that when the government
政府时的例外情况
commands us to sin such as in acts 5
命令我们犯罪，如行为5
when they told Peter and John to not
当他们告诉彼得和约翰没有
preach the gospel any more they said we
他们说我们不再传福音
will obey God not man but short of that
将服从神不是人，但缺 的是
we obey the government and of course
当然，我们服从政府
also Christian children living at home
基督教儿童也住在家里
obey their parents Ephesians 6 1 through
服从他们的父母以弗所书6 1到
4 so in every Christian life our life is
4所以在我们生命的每一个基督徒生活中
a life of submission for Christian women
为基督徒女性服务的生活
there's one other Authority and that's
那是另外一个权威机构
the husband the scriptures are clear on
丈夫的经文是明确的
this
这个
first Corinthians 11:13 there 11:3 says
哥林多前书11:13有11：3说：
but I want you to understand that Christ
但我希望你明白基督
is the head of every man and the man is
是 每个男人 的头， 男人是
the head of a woman and God is the head
一个女人和头神是头
of Christ Ephesians 5:22 wives be
基督以弗所书5:22妻子是
subject to your husband's as to the Lord
受你丈夫对主的影响
I think where people get confused
我想人们会感到困惑
sometimes is this idea that the husband
有时这个想法就是丈夫
isn't in submission to anyone and the
没有提交给任何人和
husband is completely completely an
丈夫完全是一个
authority over the wife and so the wife
对妻子和妻子的权威
is in this much different kind of life
在这种不同的生活中
but for the Christian who's obeying the
但对于那些服从的基督徒来说
word it really isn't a much different
它真的没有太大的不同
life we're all living lives of
生活我们都过着生活
submission if we're obeying the word
如果我们遵守这个词，那就提交
the wife just has one more person to
妻子只有一个人
submit to let's think about a few
提交让我们考虑几个
practical principles of submission the
提交的实际原则
Bible teaches that the marriage is a
圣经教导说婚姻是一种
relationship in which one person has
一个人有的 关系
authority and the other is subject to
权威和另一方受制于
that Authority
那个权威
so wives are to respect their husbands
所以妻子要尊重他们的丈夫
and to subject themselves themselves to
并使自己受制于
the leadership of the husband for a
丈夫的领导
woman of God to accomplish this
上帝的女人要做到这一点
effectively corresponding words are
有效对应的词是
essential commit yourself to following
必须承诺遵循
the husband's leadership and then tell
丈夫的领导，然后告诉
him that that's your decision when your
他，那是你的决定
husband glorifies God by leading you
丈夫通过引导你来荣耀上帝
according to the word thank him express
根据谢谢他 的话 来表达
your appreciation for his faithful work
感谢他的忠诚工作
what about times where you believe that
什么时候你相信这一点
he is acting speaking or choosing in
他正在演讲或选择
opposition to God's Word that happens
反对上帝发生的话语
respectfully bring up the issue if you
恭敬地提出这个问题
think about it we all do that in all of
考虑一下，我们都会这样做
our relationships with authorities over
我们与当局的关系
us respectfully bring up the issue and
我们恭敬地提出这个问题
make your objective clear your purpose
让你的目标明确你的目的
is to have this conversation so that he
是为了让他这次谈话
would best honor God by leading the
通过领导最好的方式来荣耀上帝
family according to the Scriptures your
根据圣经你的 家庭
purpose is to help by initiating
目的是通过启动来帮助
discussion offer your help in discussing
讨论提供了你的讨论帮助
the word in figuring out these decisions
找出这些决定的话
use the word as the basis of whatever
用这个词作为任何基础
you say don't mix in the hurtful or
你说不要混在有害的或
controlling words or any sinful motives
控制言语或任何有罪的动机
and then in the end communicate that
然后最后沟通
you'll follow his final choice on how to
你将按照他的最终选择如何做
best obey the word in that situation
在那种情况下最好遵守这个词
what are the exceptions same as with our
有什么例外与我们的相同
government if he's telling you to sin
政府，如果他告诉你犯罪
don't do it that passage in 1st Peter 3
不要在第一彼得3那段经文那样做
the wife who's married to the man who is
嫁给那个男人的妻子
not obedient to the word that happens a
不顺从发生的那个词
number of ways sometimes women who are
许多方式有时女人谁是
Christians marry an unbeliever and then
基督徒嫁给一个不信的人然后
later they realize they did the wrong
后来他们意识到他们做错了
thing but they're married now sometimes
事情， 但他们现在有时会结婚
two unbelievers marry and then the woman
两个不信的人结婚，然后是那个女人
becomes a Christian but the man doesn't
成为一个基督徒，但男人没有
you think about you think about that
你想到你想到这一点
God's counsel to that woman in verses 1
在第1节中，上帝对那女人的忠告
& 2 is to be this example of the godly
＆2是这个敬虔的例子
woman how does God change his heart how
女人怎么会改变他的心如何
does God say hey husband who's
上帝说嘿老公是谁
disobedient to the word I really AM God
不听话我真的是上帝
and my word is true and the gospel is
我的话是真的，福音是
true because he's observing her behavior
是的， 因为他正在观察她的行为
but then mixed into that is the woman
然后混合成那个女人
who is committed to God above the
谁在上面承诺上帝
husband she will not sin if he tells her
丈夫，如果他告诉她，她不会犯罪
to she will oppose him completely if he
如果他 ， 她会完全反对他
tells her to sin she does what is right
告诉她犯罪，她做了正确的事
and she isn't frightened by any fear let
她没有被任何恐惧让受惊
her see love another one of the wife's
她看到了另一个妻子的爱
roles is to love first Peter 1:22 tells
彼得1:22讲述的角色就是先爱
us this to love with the love of God is
我们这爱上帝的爱就是
to be an identifying mark of all true
成为所有真实的识别标志
Christians so marriage is one
基督徒所以婚姻是一体的
relationship that is for life and if
生命的关系 和如果
love is to be the characteristic of the
爱是成为的特征
Christian woman in all relationships
所有关系中的基督徒女人
certainly it should be in the marriage
当然应该是在婚姻中
how can the Christian wife love her
基督徒的妻子怎能爱她
husband convince your husband that you
丈夫说服你的丈夫，你
love him
爱他
communicated in different ways wives who
以不同的方式传达了妻子们
share the burdens of the husband
分担丈夫的负担
who walk through life together who care
一起走过生活的人
for him women who allow their husband
对他来说，允许丈夫的女人
into their soul and allow them to love
进入他们的灵魂并让他们去爱
the wife these are acts of love so are
妻子这些都是爱的行为
appreciating your man and speaking to
感谢你的男人，并与他交谈
him about things that are going on
关于正在发生的事情
inside other important biblical things
在其他重要的圣经事物里面
in all relationships are part of this
在所有的关系是 这部分
love forgive him know him encourage him
爱原谅他知道他鼓励他
strengthen him through studying the word
通过研究这个词加强他
together keep them accountable in his
让他们对自己负责
service and commitments to God the man
服务和对上帝的承诺
who is so loved by his wife rejoices
被妻子深深喜爱的人很高兴
greatly is benefited immensely and
非常受益匪浅
regards the worth of his excellent wife
尊重他优秀妻子的价值
as far above jewels such a woman brings
远远超过这样一个女人带来的珠宝
great glory to God
荣耀归于上帝
a fourth role for the wife is in Genesis
妻子的第四个角色是创世记
2:18 20 or to 18 to 25 be a suitable
2:18 20或18至25是合适的
helper God created Eve to be a suitable
帮助上帝创造了夏娃是一个合适的人
helper for man the idea of the words is
帮助男人的想法是
they fit together perfectly and that's
他们适合完美地结合在一起，这就是
that's part of the role of the woman in
那是女人角色的一部分
in the husband's pursuit of becoming
在丈夫的追求成为
more like Christ perhaps also in the
更像基督或许也是在
areas of love and communication wisdom
爱和沟通智慧的领域
how he relates to other people and
他如何与其他人和他人联系
decision-making there are probably
决策有可能
things in every marriage where the wife
妻子在每个婚姻中的事情
excels and the husband does not be the
擅长和丈夫不是
suitable helper help him become great at
合适的助手帮助他变得擅长
your strengths and then II do him good
你的优点，然后我做他好
and not harm proverbs 31 12 she does him
并且不伤害谚语31 12她做了他
good
好
not harm all the days of his life this
这 对他生命中的所有日子都没有伤害
is the summary statement of the good
是善的总结陈述
Christian wife to her husband it's the
基督徒的妻子对她的丈夫是这样的
direction of everything she does it
她做的每件事的方向
expresses the fruit of a heart that is
表达了心脏是的水果
purposed on number one honoring God and
旨在纪念上帝和
therefore number two on loving her
因此爱她的第二号
husband as Christ loved her and also
丈夫就像基督爱她一样
submitting to respecting and helping the
提交尊重和帮助
husband Roman numeral numeral 3 how to
丈夫罗马数字数字3如何
help wives live the biblical roles in
帮助妻子过上圣经中的角色
this section I'm providing some
这部分我提供了一些
important principles for biblically
圣经的重要原则
counseling wives I'm going to give you
咨询妻子我会给你
just a little brief information for each
只是每个人的简短信息
one I think each of these will benefit
我认为其中每一项都会受益
you greatly when you're sitting across
当你坐在对面的时候，你非常感兴趣
the table from a Christian wife in
来自基督徒妻子的桌子
counseling a focus your counsel II as
为你的律师II提供咨询
God on God most participants in troubled
上帝对大多数参与者感到困扰
marriages whether they are men or women
婚姻无论是男性还是女性
do not know how to selflessly serve nor
不知道如何无私地为自己服务
do they seek God's glory above
他们在上面寻求上帝的荣耀吗？
everything else comparing oneself with
比较自己的一切
God instead of one spouse may lead to
上帝而不是配偶可能导致
replacing animosity with the camaraderie
用友情取代仇恨
of pursuing sanctification leaving
追求成圣离开
father and mother is sometimes the root
父亲和母亲有时是根
issue of the problems it is vital for
问题的问题至关重要
Christian husbands and wives to hear the
基督徒的丈夫和妻子听到了
truth of the Scriptures to repent of sin
悔改罪的圣经真理
and strive to obey the word the joy of a
并努力服从一个快乐的词
vibrant growing bond with God through
通过与上帝充满活力的联系
the Scriptures is a greater force than
圣经比一个更大的力量
the most difficult hardships in marriage
婚姻中最艰难的艰辛
each of those points encompasses a
这些要点中的每一个都包含一个
number of biblical counseling cases that
圣经咨询案件数
my wife has had with Christian wives and
我的妻子已与基督教的妻子曾和
that we have where we've ministered to a
我们已经在哪里服务了
couple together
夫妻俩一起
important implications of the scriptures
经文的重要含义
another important thing to help wives
另一个帮助妻子的重要事情
live those biblical roles that we
过我们那些圣经的角色
started with gather data on words tone
开始收集关于语气的数据
and motives each revival commitment for
每个复兴承诺的动机和动机
counselors it is a privilege to walk
辅导员走路是一种荣幸
alongside Christian women during marital
在婚姻期间与基督徒妇女一起
adversity serving them no matter how
逆境为他们提供服务，无论怎样
long or how difficult the road becomes
道路变得漫长或艰难
it's so important for the Christian
这对基督徒来说非常重要
biblical counsellor to be committed to
圣经辅导员需要承担
serving their counsel a because of this
投放中，因为这样他们的一个律师
whenever it is physically possible women
每当有可能是女性的时候
should counsel women also D work with
应该咨询女性也与D合作
each counsel II at the present level of
目前各级的每位律师二
spiritual maturity for the more mature
精神成熟为更成熟
strongly challenged them to obey the
强烈要求他们服从
scripture and growth for the unruly
经文和不守规矩的增长
thinking about the first Thessalonians
思考第一个帖撒罗尼迦人
5:14 terminology admonish and be patient
5:14术语告诫并要耐心等待
for the Christian woman who is weak help
对于弱势帮助的基督徒女人
her and be patient for the unbeliever do
她对不信的人要耐心
not counsel her as if overcoming sin as
不要劝告她好像克服罪恶一样
possible regard that as pre counseling
可以认为是作为预先咨询
your meeting with her your purpose is
你与她的会面是你的目的
communicating the gospel another point
传播福音的另一点
for the unbeliever in the case of
对于不信的人而言
serious or potential law breaking sins
严重或潜在的违法犯罪
give practical direction if if a husband
如果是丈夫，请给出实际的指示
and wife are counseling a husband and
和妻子正在辅导丈夫和
wife and the counsel these are both
妻子和律师这些都是
spiritually equal to each other expects
在精神上彼此等于期望
the most change and work from the
最多的变化和工作从
husband
丈夫
and II it's so important for us as we
这对我们来说和我们一样重要
prepare as we communicate the truths of
准备好我们传达的真相
God's Word to speak those truths of the
上帝的话要说出那些真理
word from a heart that knows God's grace
来自一颗知道上帝恩典的心的话
will be sufficient for you as the
对你来说就足够 了
counselor even in the difficult cases
辅导员即使在困难的情况下
and also for that person who you're
还有你那个人
serving what about the husband who
为丈夫服务呢
physically harms his wife the Elders
身体伤害他的妻子长老
ministry the ministry of other men in
中国其他人的事工
the church and other families in the
教会和其他家庭
church and the law our God's
教会和法律我们的上帝
instruments to punish or discipline the
惩罚或惩罚的工具
man and to protect the woman and the
男人和保护女人和女人
children when properly protected by her
孩子受到她的适当保护
elders her nation's laws and the other
长老是她的国家的法律和另一个
resources of the church the Christian
基督徒教会的资源
woman is free to flourish as a strong
女人可以自由地蓬勃发展
and dignified servant of God even in the
上帝的尊严仆人，即使是在上帝
difficult situations consider these
困难的情况考虑这些
truths regarding a wife's difficult
关于妻子的困难的真相
times a sinning husband who has neither
无罪的丈夫
broken the law committed adultery nor is
打破通奸的法律也不是
under church discipline but he's just a
在教会纪律下但他只是一个
difficult man to live with so we don't
难以忍受的人，所以我们不这样做
have church discipline going on we don't
我们不遵守教会纪律
have the law involved but he's just a
有法律，但他只是一个
difficult man this woman needs to
很难男人这个女人需要
believe that 1st Corinthians 10:13 is
相信哥林多前书10:13是
true no matter how hard it is to live
无论生活多么艰难都是如此
under the same roof is that man each day
在同一屋檐下，每天都是那个男人
she is not being tempted beyond what
她没有被诱惑超越什么
she's able God will give her the
她能够上帝给她了
strength to honor him in those difficult
在那些困难中尊重他的力量
times as any other trial I'd also
次为任何其他审判我还
encourage you in this way with the
用这种方式鼓励你
difficult marriage cases the biblical
困难的婚姻案件符合圣经
counselor is responsible for speaking
辅导员负责发言
the scriptures accurately not for the
经文准确不适合
response of the counsel
律师的回应
each week we should measure our work as
每周我们应该衡量我们的工作
a biblical counselor by how well God was
一位圣经的辅导员，看上帝是多么好
honored and by how well the word was
很荣幸，这个词有多好
communicated and by our love and care
沟通，并通过我们的爱和关怀
for the council 'is not by the reaction
为该局 “不是由反应
of the council ii sometimes you have
理事会ii有时你有
marriage cases where the result of it is
婚姻案件的结果是
not change at that moment but you can be
在那一刻没有改变，但你可以
confident that the truth of the word
相信这个词的真相
that that you spoke to that wife or in
那个你和那个妻子说话 的人
the case of couples that man and that
男人和那个夫妻的情况
woman God will continue to use those in
女人神将继续使用那些
in convicting their hearts of sin and
在罪中定罪他们的心
pointing them toward repentance long
指着他们长期忏悔
after the day they stopped meeting with
过了一天，他们停止了会面
you point for how to counsel wives who
你指出如何为妻子提供咨询
are not living the biblical roles first
不是首先要遵守圣经的角色
regarding change first John 5 3 through
关于改变约翰5 3通过
5 between salvation in heaven our task
5天堂拯救我们的任务
is to overcome sin in Galatians 5 16 and
是为了克服加拉太书中的罪恶5 16和
17 the Christian denies self and obeys
17 基督徒否认自己并服从
God it's important for the Christian
上帝对基督徒来说很重要
wife to view the most important
妻子要看最重要的
relationship as what's going on between
两者之间的关系
her and the Lord and not what's going on
她和上帝，而不是发生了什么
between her and her husband so the
她和她的丈夫之间如此
change is overcoming sin in her own life
变化正在克服自己生命中的罪恶
for the sake of honoring and glorifying
为了纪念和荣耀
God regardless of what the husband is or
上帝无论丈夫是什么或是什么
is not doing when the shoe is on the
当鞋子在鞋子上的时候没有做
other foot that's my counsel for the man
另一只脚是我对这个男人的 忠告
as well
同样
hope is vital for a woman to become an
希望对于女人成为一个女人来说至关重要
excellent wife she needs to know that by
优秀的妻子，她需要通过知道
God's grace she is able to live the word
上帝的恩典，她能够活出这个词
that she's not tempted beyond what she's
她没有超越她的诱惑力
able that there is sufficient grace from
能够有足够的恩典来自
God and the power of Christ she needs to
上帝和她需要的基督的力量
live in a closed walk with the Lord
与主住在一起
where she's casting or anxieties on him
她在哪里投掷或焦虑
and choosing to not be that contentious
并选择不那么有争议
woman
女人
there's a great joy in seeing couples
看到情侣，我们感到非常高兴
both change where the final result of
两者都改变​​了最终结果
counseling is a man who is honoring God
咨询是一个尊重上帝的人
greatly and a woman who's honoring God
伟大和一个尊重上帝的女人
greatly but in the in the cases where
很大，但在其中的情况下
only one is committed to honoring God
只有一个人致力于尊重上帝
whether it's the man or the woman that
无论是男人还是女人说
person's life changes dramatically
人的生活发生了巨大的变化
because for the man or the woman and in
因为对于男人还是女人，并
this case we're talking about the woman
这个案子我们谈的是那个女人
if her purpose is bringing glory and
如果她的目的是带来荣耀和
honor to God regardless of what the
不管是什么，尊敬上帝
husband does or doesn't do she is at
丈夫做或不做她在
peace because she's accomplishing the
和平， 因为她正在完成
goal of the day she's she is doing the
她正在做的那一天的目标
good works that God has prepared
上帝所预备的善行
beforehand for her to walk in she is
事先她走在 她
bringing glory to her God and in the
把荣耀带给她的上帝和她的上帝
midst of all that there's something
在所有的东西中间
great going on between her and him the
伟大的事情她和他之间
Lord is strengthening her the Lord is
主正在加强她的主
her refuge the Lord is for strength
她的避难所，主是为了力量
there are resources on following your
有跟随你的资源
outline what you have there is you've
概述你拥有的东西
got you've got scriptures for the wife a
你得到了妻子的经文a
topical study on the roles of the wife
关于妻子角色的专题研究
useful information you also have a
有用的信息你也有
collection of common implications of the
收集的共同含义
wife who is striving to live the
正在努力过世的妻子
biblical roles there's a corresponding
圣经角色有一个对应的
one of those four men in the husband
丈夫中的四个男人中的一个
study from a couple hours ago
从几个小时前开始学习
those are both from our ministry and
这些都来自我们的事工和
then you've got journal with scripture
然后你有经文的日记
for the wife and there's also the
对于妻子而且还有
journal with scripture for husbands from
来自丈夫的经文杂志
your in your notebook from a couple of
你的笔记本中有几个
hours ago those are useful you'll notice
几个小时前， 你会注意到 这些是有用的
that the the journal was Scripture for
该杂志是为圣经
the wife is broken into the three main
妻子被打成三个主要的
roles that the wife has scripture for
角色的妻子有经文的
each and then the journal where she's
每一个，然后是她所在的期刊
thinking through each day how is she
每天都在思考她是怎么回事
doing and honoring God and living out
做和尊敬上帝和生活
these scriptures by the way we look
这些经文就像我们看的那样
journals with Scripture yesterday we saw
我们看到昨天有经文的期刊
one of them and there are those in your
其中之一， 还有你的
class notes today at the bottom of page
课程笔记今天在页面底部
154 is the website where you can get the
154 是您可以获得的网站
whole collection of those if you just go
如果你去，那些完整的收藏
to that website listed at the bottom of
到底部列出的那个网站
page 154 and and then go to Bible
第154页，然后去圣经
resources journals with Scripture you'll
资源期刊与圣经你会
find a variety of journals with
找到各种各样的期刊
Scripture like that the word to wives
圣经就像妻子这个词
and counselors to the Christian life
和基督徒生活的辅导员
here is the summary of it all be strong
这里总结一切都很强大
for Peter 3 says that be strong
因为彼得3说要坚强
Christian woman be dignified
基督徒女人要有尊严
that's the proverbs 31 woman fear
这是谚语31 女人的恐惧
nothing other than God first Peter 3 5
除了上帝第一个彼得3 5
proverbs 31 25 says this about the great
箴言31 25说，这对伟大
Christian woman strength and dignity are
基督徒女人的力量和尊严都是
her clothing and she laughs at the time
她的衣服，她当时笑了
to come she is fearless because her
来她是无所畏惧， 因为她
trust is in God first Peter 3 6 do what
信赖是在上帝的第一个彼得36做什么
is right without being frightened by any
没有被任何人吓坏是正确的
fear
恐惧
the wife who follows God's Word he is
遵循上帝之道的妻子
strong in the Lord she serves God and
在主里，她服侍上帝和
she trusts God as a strong woman she
她相信上帝是一个坚强的女人，她
disciplines young children and she is an
纪律幼儿和她是一个
example of faith admits amidst adversity
信仰的例子在逆境中承认
whether that adversity comes from her
这种逆境是否来自她
husband or the kids or from outside the
丈夫或孩子或从外
home be strong
家很坚强
listen to these verses from proverbs 31
从谚语中听这些经文31
she opens her mouth with wisdom and the
她打开她的嘴，用智慧和
teaching of kindness is on her tongue
仁慈的教导在她的舌头上
proverbs 31 27 she looks well to the
谚语31 27她看起来很好
ways of her household and she does not
她的家庭方式， 她没有
eat the bread of idleness she is a
吃她懒散的面包
leader she's a teacher she's strong
领导她是老师，她很坚强
proverbs 31:30 charm is deceitful and
谚语31:30 魅力是骗人的
beauty is vain but a woman who fears the
美丽是徒劳的，但是一个害怕的女人
Lord is to be praised there is it is it
主应该受到称赞它就是它
is the great treasure for a Christian
是基督徒的宝贵财富
husband to have a Christian wife who
丈夫要有一个基督徒的妻子
fears the Lord proverbs 31:10 says it
敬畏耶和华箴言31:10说
this way an excellent wife who can find
这样一个可以找到的优秀妻子
she is far more precious than jewels
她比珠宝更珍贵
Julie and I have is our identity
朱莉和我有我们的身份
striving to become more like Christ and
努力变得更像基督和
helping each other to do that me because
互相帮助，因为我
the word says to help her grow in
这个词是为了帮助她成长
sanctification and her because the word
成圣和她因为这个词
says to be my suitable helper and so
说是我的助手适宜等
that's what we're striving to do with
这就是我们正在努力做的事情
God's help but indeed to be married to
上帝的帮助，但确实要结婚
someone who is a woman who fears the
某人是一个害怕女人的女人
Lord an excellent wife I don't think
上帝是一位出色的妻子，我不认为
there's a greater treasure for a man
对于一个男人来说，这是一个更大的财富
there isn't for me outside of our
在我们之外没有我
relationship with the Lord Himself I'd
与主自己我会关系
like to take a couple of minutes until
喜欢花几分钟直到
the end of our time to talk about some
我们谈谈一些时间的结束
actual biblical counseling cases some
一些实际的圣经辅导案例
great Christian women women that Julie
伟大的基督徒女性女性，朱莉
and I have had the privilege of meeting
我有幸见面了
with
同
one was Clarisse when Clarisse came to
当Clarisse来到时，一个是Clarisse
us she came for Biblical counseling with
我们来参加圣经辅导
her husband because she worked in an
她的丈夫， 因为她在一个
office with a bunch of Christian women
办公室与一群基督徒妇女
who went to our church she had been
谁曾去过我们的教堂
married for about two years they had a
结婚约两年，他们有一个
baby and her husband had been unfaithful
宝贝和她的丈夫一直不忠
he had committed adultery with a woman
他和一个女人犯了通奸罪
at his work he came along also so Julie
在他的工作中他也是如此朱莉
and I are sitting here with Clarisse and
我和Clarisse一起坐在这里
her husband of course there is no
她的丈夫当然没有
biblical counseling for the unbeliever
为不信的人提供圣经辅导
we started with the gospel we found out
我们从我们发现的福音开始
neither of them had responded to the
他们都没有回应 了
gospel and faith and repentance neither
福音，信仰和悔改都没有
wanted to so we went through the gospel
我们想要通过福音
in some detail that day that day the
那天那天的一些细节
first session of biblical counseling
第一节圣经辅导
before we even talked about marriage she
在我们谈论婚姻之前她
committed her life to Christ that was
致力于她的生活基督，这是
exciting Clarice's husband did not as we
令人兴奋的克拉丽丝的丈夫没有像我们一样
met together later in that session one
在那次会议中稍后一起见面
of the things that I asked him was at
那我问的事情他是在
some point in the future if you were in
如果你在，将来会有一些意义
the same situation some other woman at
一些其他女人在同样的情况
work and you realized that adultery was
工作，你意识到通奸是
possible would you do it he said yes
可能你会这样做他说是的
according to first Peter 3 the husband
根据第一个彼得3的丈夫
and also Matthew 18 or excuse me Matthew
还有马修18或请原谅我马修
19 1 through 8 the Christian who's
19 1到8基督徒是谁
married to someone who commits adultery
结婚的人谁犯奸淫
and doesn't repent that's him can file
并且不会悔改他可以提交的内容
for divorce can biblically be divorced
离婚可以在圣经上离婚
and would be free to marry again but I
并且可以自由地再次结婚但是我
don't believe that the Scriptures
不相信圣经
command that it's an option in the times
命令它是时代的选择
that we met with clarice after that
那之后我们遇到了克拉丽斯
through discipleship and Julie's good
通过门徒训练和朱莉的好
work with her she grew greatly as a
和她一起工作， 她成长得很好
Christian woman her choice after a
基督徒女人她选择了一个
number of weeks was she wanted to remain
她希望留下几个星期
married to her husband she had the
嫁给了她的丈夫， 她有
biblical grounds for biblical divorce
圣经离婚的圣经理由
but she chose to remain married to him
但她选择和他结婚
why was that
为什么会这样
because she wanted to give it a shot
因为她想给它一个镜头
being that first Peter 3:1 and 2 women
是第一个彼得3：1和2个女人
she wanted to be an example of an
她想成为一个例子
excellent wife she wanted to be an
她想成为一名优秀的妻子
example of a woman who honored God above
一个尊重上帝的女人的例子
all else and let him see that in case
一切，让他看到，在情况
perhaps someday he would respond to the
也许有一天他会到响应
gospel and be saved that was her choice
福音， 并得救，这是她的选择
she was free to choose and that was the
她可以自由选择，那就是
one she chose what a beautiful thing it
一个她选择了什么美丽的东西呢
was to see this woman choose what she
是看到这个女人选择她
believed best honor and glorify God and
相信最好的荣誉，并荣耀上帝和
then to go through the day's the weeks
然后经历 这一周 的那一周
the months after that where she's living
她生活的那几个月之后
with her son apart from the husband
与她的儿子除了丈夫
she's mom she's breadwinner she's it's
她是妈妈，她是养家糊口的， 她就是这样
her household she's taking care of
她正在照顾她的家庭
everything but she lived as a woman who
除了她作为一个女人生活的一切
feared God she was an amazing example of
害怕上帝她是一个惊人的例子
a strong woman she was a woman of
一个坚强的女人， 她是一个女人
dignity I'm going to tell you that what
尊严我会告诉你那是什么
happened after that isn't really the
发生在那之后不是真的
important thing because what she did
重要的是因为她做了什么
then brought great glory and honor to
然后带来了巨大的荣耀和荣誉
God and will result in more jewels in
上帝，将导致更多的珠宝
that crown that she's gonna lay at the
那个她将会躺在那里的王冠
feet of Jesus Christ what a beautiful
耶稣基督的脚是多么美丽
thing to see by God's grace that man did
上帝的恩典，人类所做的事情
come to Christ I had lunch together he
来到基督我和他一起共进午餐
wanted to have lunch with me
我想跟我共进午餐
after he had started coming to church he
他开始来教堂之后
just wanted me to know he realizes what
只是想让我知道他意识到了什么
an idiot he was and his purpose in life
他是一个白痴，他的人生目标
is to bring glory and honor to Jesus
就是要为耶稣带来荣耀和荣耀
Christ and to love that woman
基督，爱那个女人
God is good
上帝是好的
the strong Christian woman brings great
坚强的基督徒女人带来伟大
glory to God one of the women that Julie
荣耀上帝是朱莉的女人之一
had a chance to meet with was a woman
有机会见到一个女人
who was married to a good Christian guy
谁嫁给了一个好基督徒家伙
he wasn't perfect but he definitely was
他并不完美，但他绝对是
working hard at leading the family that
努力领导家庭
woman's problem was the control she
女人的问题是控制她
wanted to make decisions she and she had
想做出她和她的决定
a way of controlling him actually she
控制他其实她的一种方式
had a few they were effective but so
有一些他们是有效的但是如此
they came to us and Julie worked with
他们来到美国和朱莉一起工作
that woman and through the scriptures
那个女人，通过经文
for through her realizing what the
通过她意识到了什么
scripture said about the primary
关于小学的经文说
relationship being with God the Father
与父神的关系
and not with a husband had changed her
并没有与丈夫改变了她
thinking completely the mission changed
彻底思考任务的变化
from I want everything to be exactly the
从我希望一切都完全是
way I wanted and he's getting in the way
我想要的方式，他正在妨碍我
too I want to bring glory and honor to
我也想带来荣耀和荣誉
God in every one of these parts of my
上帝在我的每一部分
life that was exciting in cases like
生活在 类似的情况下是令人兴奋
that there's communication of the truth
那是真理的沟通
of the word usually there's some kind of
这个词通常有某种
a journal where the woman is thinking
女人思考的杂志
through these scriptures day after day
通过这些经文日复一日
after day and writing about him and God
一天之后写下他和上帝
is doing what only he can do
正在做他唯一能做的事情
he's impacting the heart changing the
他正在影响心脏改变
heart forcing the heart toward
心脏迫使心脏走向
repentance and she chose to repent and
忏悔，她选择悔改和
and when she changed from one motive to
当她从一个动机变为
the other that was it
另一个是它
she was the wise woman that we talked
她是我们谈过的聪明女人
about her earlier figuring out the
关于她早先搞清楚了
details of that she didn't even need
的，她甚至不需要细节
help with but the heart was everything
帮助但心脏就是一切
how exciting it is to see that and as I
看到这一点和我一样令人兴奋
think I mentioned too many times but one
我想我提到的次数太多了
of the really fun things is being in
真正有趣的事情在于
church on Sunday morning and sometimes
教会在星期天早上，有时候
you know you're singing you're looking
你知道你在唱歌，你正在寻找
around and
周围和
you happen to notice there's Clarisse
你碰巧注意到有Clarisse
and her husband over there they've been
和她的丈夫在那里他们一直都是
married for ten years now that little
结婚十年 ，现在小
boy is I think nine they have another
男孩，我认为九，他们有另一个
child there's that woman that Julie
孩子那个女人，朱莉
counseled who is this great treasure to
劝告谁是这个伟大的宝藏
her husband and a great example to other
她的丈夫和一个很好的例子给其他
women and even more a great honor to God
女人，甚至是对上帝的荣幸
so those are exciting things I hope
所以这些是我希望的令人兴奋的事情
these things are practical for you today
这些东西对你来说很实用
and also as resources in the future
并且还作为未来的资源
you
您